<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The custom of the mannor of Paynswicke taken out of the decree in Chancery, and carefully examined for the benfit of the tenants or others that may be concerned. By Thomas Loveday, in the year 1687.</title>
            <author>Loveday, Thomas.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1688</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 67 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 35 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A88608</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L3235A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R230715</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99896441</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99896441</idno>
            <idno type="VID">154272</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A88608)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 154272)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2408:18)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The custom of the mannor of Paynswicke taken out of the decree in Chancery, and carefully examined for the benfit of the tenants or others that may be concerned. By Thomas Loveday, in the year 1687.</title>
                  <author>Loveday, Thomas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>55, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>printed in the year, 1688.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Landlord and tenant --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:3"/>
            <p>THE CUSTOM Of the Mannor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> Taken out Of the Decree in Chancery, and carefully Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amined For the benfit of the Tenants or others that may be concerned.</p>
            <p>By <hi>Thomas Loveday,</hi> in the Year 1687.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the Year, 1688.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="royal_attestation">
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:154272:4"/>
            <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
               <opener>
                  <signed>JAcobus Dei grac. Angliae, Scotiae, Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciae et Hibern. Rex fidei defenſor. &amp;c.</signed>
                  <salute>Omnibus ad quos preſentes Litt. per veniunt Salut.</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>in videmus jus prox. irrotula mentum ejuſdam decreti ſive. judicij coram nobis in Cancellar. noſtra Inter. Johan. Hamond a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lias Jorden, et aliis Tenand. Manerij de Paynſwicke in Com. Glouc. queren. et Henr. Jernegan Armiger. et aliis Defenſ. nuper fac. et redit in Rotulis cum. Cancellar. noſt. predic. irrotulat ac ibidem. de Recordo reſiden. in haec verba.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:154272:4"/>
               <opener>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>JAmes</hi> by the grace of God, of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Scotland, France and Ireland</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </signed>
                  <salute>To all to whom theſe preſent Letters ſhall come greeting;</salute>
               </opener>
               <p>we have ſen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the Inrollment of a certain Decree of Judgment before us in our Chancery, between <hi>John Hamond</hi> alias <hi>Jordan,</hi> and other Tenants of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> in the County of <hi>Glouceſter</hi> Plaintiffs; and <hi>Henry Jerne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> and others, Defendants late<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly made and Inrolled in the Rolls of our ſaid Court of Chancery, and there re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining upon Record in theſe words, <hi>&amp;c</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:154272:5"/>
            <head>THE CUSTOM Of the Manner of <hi>Paynſwicke.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WHere heretofore <hi>John Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond,</hi> alias <hi>Jorden, John May, John Brown, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Byſhoppe, Edmond Flecher, Richard Gardner, Thomas Tayler, Thomas Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coppe, Richard Coocke and William Barns</hi> an Infant within Age, by <hi>Gyles Charter</hi> and <hi>Agnes</hi> his Wife, his Guardians, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainants, for and in the behalf of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves and divers others, being all of them ſeveral Copy-holders and cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of divers ſeveral cuſtomary and Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py-hold Meſſuages, Lands and Tenements parcel of the Mannor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> in the County of <hi>Glouceſter;</hi> and time out of minde demiſable, and uſed to be demiſed in
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:154272:5"/>grants and admitances, by Copy of Court Roll of the ſaid Mannor, to the ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker or takers thereof, by the words <hi>Sibi &amp; Suis,</hi> which words make and create within the ſaid Mannor, a cuſtomary e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate of inheritance in fee ſimple at the will of the Lord, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, there exhibited their Bill of complaint into the honorable <hi>Court of Chancery</hi> againſt <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
               <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, <abbr>Eſq</abbr> and <hi>Thomas Neaſt</hi> Defendants, and on the contrary ſide, the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the el<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainants, did afterward exhibite their Bill of complaints into the ſaid honorable <hi>Court of Chancery</hi> againſt the ſaid <hi>John Mayo, John Browne,</hi> and the reſt of the ſaid Copy-holders and Tenants of the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick</hi> Defendants; in and by which ſaid firſt Bill, the ſaid Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants did declare, that whereas the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, in the Eight and Twentieth year of the late <hi>Queen Elizabeth,</hi> and before was ſeiſed in his Demeaſne as of Fee or Fee-Tail of and in the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick,</hi> with the Right Members and Appurtean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces thereof: And the ſaid Complaynants
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:154272:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <hi>John Mayo, John Brown</hi> and <hi>Thomas By ſhopp,</hi> and their Anceſters, and others the then Cuſtomary Tenants and Copy-hold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick,</hi> then and long time before that, had and held ſeverally to them and their Heirs, at the will of the Lord, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, divers ſeveral Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py-hold and Cuſtomary Meſſuages, Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments, parcel of the ſaid Mannor, time out of mind there uſed and accuſtomed to be granted and demiſed by Copy of Court Roll of the ſaid Mannor of Eſtates of Inheritance in Fee-ſimple, by the words <hi>(ſibe &amp; ſuis)</hi> at the will of the Lord, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, and within the ſaid Mannor then and time out of mind there were and had been, and ought to be uſed and accuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed divers Antient laudable Cuſtoms touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Copy-hold and Cuſtomary Meſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ages, Lands and Tenements there, and namely and particularly amongſt others; that the Heir of every Copy-holder and Cuſtomary Tenant dying ſeized of ſuch cuſtomary Eſtate, of and in any Copy-hold or Cuſtomary Maſſuages, Lands or Tenaments of the ſaid Mannor, was to be, and ought, and was uſed to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:154272:6"/>and admitted Tenant of the ſame cuſtomary Meſſuages, Lands and Tena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments at the Court of the ſaid Mannor, upon reaſonable tender and requeſt in that behalf, for the fine of one years Rent only; and that the cuſtomary Tenants of the ſaid Mannor by the cuſtom there, ought to have all the Herbage and Panage of the common woods, and common Hills, and the Lords Waſtes of the ſaid Mannor, and in or about the Month of <hi>March,</hi> in the ſaid Eight and Twentieth year of the ſaid late Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> ſome diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences grew and were like to ariſe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, then Lord of the ſaid Mannor, and the then Copy-holders, or Cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of the ſaid Mannor; and the ſaid Tenants being unwilling to contend in ſuit of Law with their Landlord, did in dutiful and ſubmiſſive manner make means unto the ſaid Maſter <hi>Jernegan</hi> for a good and peaceable end, with his love and good will; and the ſaid Maſter <hi>Jernegan</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Gentleman well inclined unto a peace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble end; and the ſaid then Copy-hold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers deſire the ſame, it was thereupon a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greed and directed between them, that the Cuſtoms of the ſaid Mannor, whereof
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:154272:7"/>there was or might be likelyhood of queſtion or controverſie, ſhould, and might be conſidered of, and known in ſome certainty, and truly ſet down in Writing, to be allowed of, and held by the Lord and Tenants for quiet of them and their Poſterity: And thereupon ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry of the Cuſtoms of the ſaid Mannor were then remembred and conſidered of, and agreed upon, and were ſet down in Writing indented, made between the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> on the one Party, and the then Copy-holders and Cuſtomary Tenants of the ſaid Mannor, of the other Party; and Enterchangably by them Sealed and Delivered, the Tenor and Effect where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of is as followeth, that is to ſay.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>This Indenture,</hi> made the Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth day of <hi>March,</hi> in the Eight and Twentieth year of the Raign of <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth,</hi> by the Grace of God of <hi>England, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> Queen Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Between <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> of <hi>Coſſey</hi> in the County of <hi>Norfolke</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> and Lord of the Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick</hi> in the County of <hi>Glouceſter</hi> of the one Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; and all the Cuſtomary Tenants of the Lordſhip and Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick</hi> aforeſaid, of the other Party, Witneſſeth,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:154272:7"/>that whereas of late years, ſome Queſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and variance hath been moved be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan,</hi> and his Cuſtomary Tenants of the ſaid Lordſhip and Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick,</hi> about divers and ſundry Articles of the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor; the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> tendering the Quietneſs, Love and good Will of his ſaid Tenants, and in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration of the hope of the like dutiful Service, good Will and Behavour, to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards him and his Poſterity hereafter, always to be performed by the ſaid Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants and their Heirs and Aſſigns, willing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly as to his late Father and Mother, and others of his Anceſtors hath been hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſhewed, done and accompliſhed, at the humble Suit and Petition of all the ſaid Tenants tendered and exhibited to the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan,</hi> the Twentieth day of <hi>March,</hi> before the date of theſe preſents, by the mediation of <hi>John Dere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> Gentleman, Serveyor general to the ſaid <hi>Henry:</hi> Doth by theſe preſents for him and his Heirs Ratifie, Confirm and Eſtabliſh theſe Articles, as in this <hi>Inden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture</hi> are expreſſed to ſtand, be and remain as true and perpetual Articles, of the Cuſtom of the Mannor of <hi>Paynſwick</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:154272:8"/>
            <p n="1">I. <hi>Imprimis,</hi> The Cuſtom is, and time out of mind hath been, that the Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of the ſaid Mannor do hold their Maſſuages, Lands and Tenements by Copy of Court Roll, <hi>Sibi &amp; ſuis;</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by they have an Eſtate of Inheritance to them and their Heirs, according to the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor there.</p>
            <p n="2">II. <hi>Item,</hi> The Cuſtomary Tenants there, from time out of mind have uſed, and ought to pay their Rents yearly at four Terms in the year uſual and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſtomed <hi>(viz.)</hi> The <hi>Annutiation</hi> of our <hi>Lady,</hi> the <hi>Nativity</hi> of Saint <hi>John Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſt,</hi> Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch-Angel, and the <hi>Birth</hi> of our <hi>Lord,</hi> and ſhall have a Reeve to gather the ſame, after the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, and the ſame Rents ſhall pay to the Lord, or his Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, accordingly, within Eight and Twenty days next after every of the ſaid Feaſts.</p>
            <p n="3">III. <hi>Item,</hi> That one of the Cuſtomary Tenants being an Homager, ought to be Reeve, and to collect and gather the Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomary Rents, Revenes and Profits of the ſaid Mannor, and ſhall pay the ſame to the Lord or his Officers, within Eight and Twenty days, next after every of the
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:154272:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>ſaid Feaſts of the <hi>Anuntiation</hi> of our <hi>Lady,</hi> the <hi>Nativity</hi> of Saint <hi>John Baptiſt,</hi> Saint <hi>Michael</hi> the Archangel, and the <hi>Birth</hi> of our <hi>Lord,</hi> where the Lord or his Officers ſhall appoint, by his or their Precept; and alſo againſt every audit of the Lord to be kept for the ſaid Mannor ſhall ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther and leavy the extract of the Court, and make a true Account thereof, and pay the ſame at the Lords Audit yearly, which Reeve ought to be elected and cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen yearly by the Homage of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor; for if ſuch Reeve ſo elected, ſhall happen to Imbeſſel, or Waſte the Lords Rent, Revenues and Profits of the ſaid Mannor; that then the ſaid Tenants are bound by their Cuſtom to anſwer the Lord the ſame Rent, Revenues and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits at the days and times aforeſald.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. <hi>Item,</hi> The Reeve upon his Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, ought to have allowance of Six and Twenty Shillings Eight Pence for his pains-taking in gathering of the ſaid Rents, which allowance hath been uſed time out of mind.</p>
            <p n="5">V. <hi>Item,</hi> There are certain other Lands, called the <hi>Thirteens,</hi> the Tenants whereof, by the Cuſtom, are bound to carry <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>eniſon</hi> for the Lord into ſuch
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:154272:9"/>place or places as the Lord ſhall appoint them, by the ſpace of one day and a night a piece, at their own charges, or elſe to ſtand to a yearly Fine of eight Pence, to the uſe of the Lord of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor at the Election of the Lord.</p>
            <p n="6">VI. <hi>Item,</hi> The Tenants by their Cuſtom, time out of mind uſed, may give and ſell their Cuſtomary Lands at their will and pleaſure, making a ſurrender of the ſame, either in open Court to the hands of the Steward for the time being, or elſe out of the Court, into the hands of the Reeve of that year or his Deputy, in the preſence of two Cuſtomary Tenants of the ſame Mannor, and the ſame ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render muſt be preſented at the next Court, or elſe the Surrender to be void, and upon every Surrender ſo made, and preſented in Court; the Lord is to have an Heriot, if the Land be Heriotable, that is to ſay, for every yard and half yard of Land, which the Tenants hold, to give or pay the beſt quick Cattle, and in default of ſuch Cattle, the beſt Houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold ſtuff or Goods of what kind ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever.</p>
            <p n="7">VII. <hi>Item,</hi> That upon every decent of any Cuſtomary Lands of Inheritance
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:154272:9"/>the Lord is to have one years Rent for his Fine, and a Heriot in mannor aforeſaid, if the Land be heriotable.</p>
            <p n="8">VIII. <hi>Item,</hi> That upon every Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render, either in Poſſeſſion or Reverſion, the Lord is to have ſeven years Rent of the thing ſo ſurrendered, for his Fine; but if any Tenant having firſt ſurrendred the Reverſion of any cuſtomary Lands, and will afterwards Surrender his Eſtate in poſſeſſion; or if any Woman that holdeth Lands and Tenements by her free Bench, according to the cuſtom, ſhall ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render her Eſtate, which ſhe hath for term of her or his Life; in theſe two kinds of Surrenders the Lord is to have but one years Rent, and a Heriot, if the Land be Heriotable upon the ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render.</p>
            <p n="9">IX. <hi>Item,</hi> At every Surrender made in Reverſion, no Heriot is due, until the Death of him or her which made ſurren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, nor none other advantages due to the Lord but the Fine only.</p>
            <p n="10">X. <hi>Item,</hi> After the death of any Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant, the Wife of the ſame Tenant, if any ſuch be, ſhall be admitted to her free Bench in the Lords Court, by the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of one Penny, to have to her during
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:154272:10"/>her Life, paying ſuch Rents, Cuſtoms and ſervices thereof, due and accuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</p>
            <p n="11">XI. <hi>Item,</hi> After the death of any ſuch Woman, the ſame Tenement or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, which were in her tenure; ſhall come and deſcend to the next Heir on the part of the Husband of the ſame Woman, and for lack of an Heir, to the next Kinſman of the ſame Husband, if no Surrender be thereof made before, after the ſaid Cuſtom, without payment of any Heriot for the Woman, which held by her free Bench, as afore is ſaid.</p>
            <p n="12">XII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Woman Inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trix die ſeized of any Tenement or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, and no ſurrender by her in her Life time made; that then all ſuch Lands or Tenements, whereof ſhe died ſeized ſhall come and deſcend to the next Heir, after the cuſtom and mannor, Paying an Heriot for the ſame Woman if it be he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riotable.</p>
            <p n="13">XIII. <hi>Item,</hi> That all Tenants by their Cuſtom time out of mind uſed, may ſell their Woods, Timber, Trees, and other Fuel and Bruſh, growing in and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on their Tenements, without licenſe of the Lord or his Officers, and that every
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:154272:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>Tenant may Let and Set his Cuſtomary Lands, or any part thereof, without li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſe of the Lord or of his Officers; and alſo to make any Quarrey, to Build or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair upon the ſame, and not otherwiſe; upon any part of his Cuſtomary Lands.</p>
            <p n="14">XIV. <hi>Item,</hi> The Tenants time out of mind have uſed at their will and plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, to Build Cottages upon their Copy-hold Tenaments, and to Let and Set the ſame without any licenſe, asking or pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing any Fine to the Lord for the ſame, ſaving that the head Tenant is to anſwer and pay the Amercements and Pains for all Treſpaſſes, as ſhall be committed by any under Tenant in the Lords Wood and Park, Demeſnes, or in any Woods or Grounds of any of the Cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants, preſented and offered by the Lords Tenants in the Court, if any of the ſaid under Tenants Eſtreted, be not able to ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie and pay the ſame.</p>
            <p n="15">XV. <hi>Item,</hi> If a Woman holding by her free Bench, do Marry ſundry Husbands, at ſundry times, yet ſhall ſhe injoy the ſame during her Life, without forfeiture thereof.</p>
            <p n="16">XVI. <hi>Item,</hi> By the Cuſtom, every yard or half-yard of Land, holden by
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:154272:11"/>Copy, after the cuſtom and manner is he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riotable, and the Heriot to be payed a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the death of the Tenant, that dieth ſeiz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed thereof, or upon the ſurrender of hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Poſſeſſion when the Reverſion was ſurren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred before.</p>
            <p n="17">XVII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants ſhall Let or Set his yard or hal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> yard of Land, which is heriotable, and a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his Deceaſe the Lord not anſwered, th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> beſt Beaſt for his Heriot, which did com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly manure the ſaid Premiſes, by th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſpace of one year next before his deceaſe or the full value thereof, that then ſuch Perſons to whom the ſame yard or hal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> yard by the Cuſtom ought to come <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhall pay to the Lord or his Officers, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in ſix Weeks next after the death of ſuch Tenants, three Pounds for every yard Land, and forty Shillings for every hal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> yard inſtead of an Heriot, and in caſe de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault be made thereof; then it ſhall be lawful for the Lord by his Officers, to<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> take one Whole years profit of ſuch yard or half yard to his own uſe and behoof in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of the ſaid Heriot.</p>
            <p n="18">XVIII. <hi>Item,</hi> That all Land, called, <hi>Mondays Thirteens, Farrendels, Burgage<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and <hi>Curtelages</hi> are not heriotable.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:154272:11" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p n="19">XIX. <hi>Item,</hi> If a Man have divers Sons, and the eldeſt dyeth having Iſſue of his Body lawfully begotten, whether it be Male or Female; and after their Grandfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther dyeth, the Iſſue of the eldeſt Brother ſhall Inherit as next Heir to the Grandfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</p>
            <p n="20">XX. <hi>Item,</hi> If a Man dyeth, having divers Daughters, and no Sons, and hath ſo many yards, or half yards of Lands as Daughters, then ſhall every Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters by the Cuſtom, have a yard or half yard Land, and the like order is with Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; but if the Tenant ſo dying, have but one yard, half yard, or one Tena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, having divers Daughters as before is ſaid, that then the ſame yard, half yard, or Tenement, by the Homage and Steward there, ſhall be priſed to the beſt value, and the price thereof to be devi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded equally amongſt the ſaid Daughters, ſaving that the eldeſt Daughter ſhall have her choice, whether ſhe will have the yard, half yard, or Tenement, or the Portion of Money to her allotted by the Homage and Steward; and if ſhe take the ſaid yard, half yard, or Tenement, then ſhe to pay the Money to her other, Siſters after the prized price.</p>
            <pb n="22" facs="tcp:154272:12"/>
            <p n="21">XXI. <hi>Item,</hi> That after the death of every Tenant that dyeth ſeized, of any Lands or Tenements within the ſaid Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip; at the next Court there holden, Proclamation ſhall be made openly, to enquire who is the right Heir of the Tenant ſo deceaſed, or who can make any claim or title to the ſame Tenure or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nures; and if at the firſt Court there come none to Challenge the ſaid Tenure or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nures, then there ſhall be Proclamation made openly at (to other) the next Court there holden in like manner as is aforeſaid, and then if none having Right come to challenge the ſame, from thence forth the Lands ſhall be Echeated to the Lord, to diſpoſe of the ſame at his Will and Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, except the next Heir that hath Right to the ſame, be beyond the Seas, or in the Kings Wars.</p>
            <p n="22">XXII. <hi>Item,</hi> That whoſoever is to be admitted Tenant to any Tenure with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid Lordſhip, ought openly to be admitted in the Court before the Homage, and to have his Copy read openly in the Court, that all Men there may hear and know that he is admitted Tenant accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly; and if any Perſon having Right to any Tenure by Inheritance, is to be admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:154272:12"/>Tenant, then he ought to be taken and preſented by the Homage; and if any challenge any Tenure by Surrender, that then the Surrender muſt be made, either in the Court openly, or elſe to be brought into the Court by credible and ſufficient witneſſes, that it may be known to the Homage, and ſo be admitted Tenant as it is aforeſaid, according to the Cuſtom there uſed time out of mind.</p>
            <p n="23">XXIII. <hi>Item,</hi> Whoſoever taketh any Tenure there of the Lord, he muſt take it either by means of Inheritance of himſelf or his Wife, or by ſurrender of ſome other that is an Heir, or elſe by means of ſome Forfeiture or Eſcheat into the Lords Hands, and it muſt be expreſſed in the Copy of the Taker, whether he takes his Tenure by right of Inheritance of himſelf or his Wife, or by ſurrender of any Perſon, or by Forfeiture or Eſcheat into the Lords Hands, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or by the Default of an Heir; to challenge it otherwiſe, no Man can take any Tenure there, nor the Lord can let it otherwiſe, by the Cuſtom there uſed time out of minde,</p>
            <p n="24">XXIV. <hi>Item,</hi> That the Tenants by their Cuſtom, ought to have the Herbage and Paunage of the common Woods
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:154272:13" rendition="simple:additions"/>and Hils, and the Lords Waſte, as time out of mind they have uſed.</p>
            <p n="25">XXV. <hi>Item,</hi> That the Tenants there, at ſuch time as the Lord of the Mannor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> ſhall not be Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morant, or Dwelling within the ſaid Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, ſhall have ſuch Strays as ſhall hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen into their Cuſtody from time to time, paying ſuch price as they ſhall be indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rently prized by the Reeve of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, and four of the Homagers to be choſen by the ſaid Reeve; the ſaid price being preſented and allowed by the Lords chief Officers, at the next Court to be holden within the ſaid Mannor.</p>
            <p n="26">XXVI. <hi>Item,</hi> The Cuſtom is, and time out of mind uſed hath been, that the Sheriff or any his Bayliffs and Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters, cannot enter within this Liberty to ſerve any Proceſs, upon any Perſon within the ſame, unleſs it be with a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandment or Subpena.</p>
            <p n="27">XXVII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Tenant doth give or ſell any part or parcel of his Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, or the whole without Surrender, it is a Forfeiture.</p>
            <p n="28">XXVIII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Tenant do let down his Tenement or any part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, being payned at two Courts, to Build
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:154272:13"/>the ſame by a certain pain, and the third Court on pain of Forfeiture, and doth not Build the ſame according to the order in the Court, taken by the Homage and the Steward, it is a Forfeit.</p>
            <p n="29">XXIX. <hi>Item,</hi> If any be an Inheritor to any Lands or Tenements, doth ſell the ſame to any Perſon or Perſons before he, or ſhe ſhall become Tenant to the Lord in his Court, and do other Suits and Services, according to the cuſtom there, it is a Forfeiture.</p>
            <p n="30">XXX. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Tenant do de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain or with-hold any Rents willingly, which are due to the Lord; or doth withdraw his Suit, and Service from the Lords Court, being not eſſoyned four general Courts together, one after another, is cauſe of Forfeiture.</p>
            <p n="31">XXXI. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Tenant do convey any Part of the Lordſhip, to any other with intent to deceive the Lord of the ſame, it is a Forfeit.</p>
            <p n="32">XXXII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Perſon do hold any Cuſtomary Lands joyntly within this Mannor, it is a Forfeiture by the Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtom.</p>
            <p n="33">XXXIII. <hi>Item,</hi> If any Reeve cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen by the Homage, ſhall refuſe to gather
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:154272:14" rendition="simple:additions"/>the Lords Rents and Profeits, or ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to beat the Office according to the Cuſtom, and to pay the Rents and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits by him levied by vertue of his Office, is cauſe of Forfeiture.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And after that,</hi> And according to the ſame Articles and Cuſtoms agreed upon, and put in Writing; the Cuſtomary Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> quietly enjoyed their Cuſtomary Meſſuages and Tenements, and were admitted Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants from time to time, and did yeild and pay all Rents and Cuſtoms according<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and according to the ſaid Cuſtom as in former and ancient times they had done, and enjoyed the ſame, and alſo there were, and time out of mind had been, within the ſaid Mannor divers other ancient Cuſtoms and Uſages, not mentioned nor ſet down in the ſaid <hi>Iudenture,</hi> and name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly by the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, the Cuſtomary Tenants thereof, have uſed to exchange their Cuſtomary Lands, or part thereof one with another, they firſt coming into the Court of the Mannor, and there paying licenſe to make ſuch exchange, and each of the ſaid Tenants ſo exchanging, paying therefore two pence a piece for every. Acre ſo exchanged, and
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:154272:14" rendition="simple:additions"/>the ſame Exchanges being from time to time Entered and Recorded in the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mannor, have been ever held and allowed as lawful; And alſo the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor there uſed was and had been, that if any cuſtomary Tenant dyed ſeized of any Cuſtomary E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate of Inheritance, of or in any cuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary Lands or Tenements of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, his Heir being under the Age of One and Twenty years, that then the next of Kin to the ſaid Heir, not Inheriota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the ſaid cuſtomary Lands, ought to have, and uſed to have the Cuſtody of the ſame Heir, of ſuch his Lands until the full Age of One and Twenty years, of ſuch Heir, yeilding account therefore unto the ſaid Heir at his full Age, the overſight, government and commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereof, to be in the Court upon charge of the Homage of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor. And whereas alſo, about three or four Years before the ſaid Bill exhibi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted on <hi>Henry Barns,</hi> Grandfather of the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>William Barns,</hi> was a copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold Tenant, and dyed ſeized of a Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold and Cuſtomary Eſtate of Inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance, in Fee-ſimple of certain copy hold Lands and Tenements, parcel of the
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:154272:15"/>ſaid Mannor, which by the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, deſcended unto <hi>Humphery Barns,</hi> Son and Heir of the ſaid <hi>Henry,</hi> which <hi>Humphery</hi> dyed ſeized of the ſaid Eſtate, and by the ſaid Cuſtom, the ſame deſcended to <hi>Henry Barns,</hi> Son and Heir of the ſaid <hi>Humphery Barns,</hi> which ſaid <hi>Henry Barns,</hi> Son of the ſaid <hi>Humphery,</hi> dyed ſeized of the ſaid Eſtate, and by the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, the ſame deſcended, and came to the Plaintiff <hi>William Barns,</hi> Brother and Heir of <hi>Henry Barns</hi> the Son; and the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>William Barns,</hi> is an Infant of the Age of Ten Years or there about, and under the Age of One and Twenty; and the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>Giles Carter,</hi> having Married the Mother of the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>William Barns,</hi> the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>William Barns,</hi> is and ought by the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, to be in the Cuſtody of the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>Giles Carter,</hi> and <hi>Agnes</hi> his Wife; all which ancient and laudable cuſtoms are and had been uſed, as the ſaid plaintiff alledged until then of late; but ſo it was as they alſo alledged by their ſaid Bill, that ſome eſtate or con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyance being lately had and made of the ſaid Mannor, by the ſaid Defendant
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:154272:15"/>
               <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, to the uſe of the other Defendant, <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, he the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, pretended and went about to call in queſtion, and to avoid divers of the ſaid Complainants Eſtates, upon pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence and ſurmiſe of ſome defects or want of Warrants, or miſtaking in the ſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ing or keeping of the Courts of the ſaid Mannor, or of the Steward that kept the ſame, or of the parties in whoſe names the ſame Courts were kept, and that therefore the admittances of ſundry of the ſaid Plaintiffs ſhould be void, which the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger gave out he would avoid, and to that end, whereas upon every diſcent of an Cuſtomary Land of Inheritance, the Lord by the Cuſtom of the ſaid Mannor, is to have one years Rent for his Fine, and the Tenant or next Heir thereupon to be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the ſame Land; the ſaid Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dnant <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, deni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that there was any ſuch Cuſtom, and alſo denied unto the ſaid Complainants, the Herbage and Paunage of the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Woods, Hils and Waſts of the ſaid Mannor, which the ancient Court Rolls of the ſaid Mannor did prove, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:154272:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>in the Defendants Cuſtody, and that the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger had of late oppreſſed the commonable Grounds, with great numbers of Sheep, &amp; had cauſed the Steward of the ſaid Mannor not to make entry of any exchange between the Cuſtomary Tenants of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, for ſuch Fines as hath been accuſtom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; and alſo the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, had made ſome grant of the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>Barns</hi> his cuſtomary Lands, of purpoſe to prejudice him being a poor Infant; and that the ſaid <hi>Henry Jerne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan</hi> the younger, had made ſome ſecret <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſes, of ſome of the ſaid Cuſtomary Lands and Premiſes, belonging to the ſaid Plaintiff, to divers Perſons unknown to them, and had commenced, or cauſed to be commenced, and threatned to bring and Proſecute divers Suits at the common Law againſt the ſaid Plaintiffs, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Premiſes, for avoiding whereof, and that the ſaid Cuſtoms might be certainly known and Eſtabli<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>'d, and for that the ſaid Defendants, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> their Stewards, had in their cuſtodies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Writings which did ſhew the ſaid C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms, without which the ſaid Plaintiffs were not able to defend themſelves at
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:154272:16"/>the common Law, but were like with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the aid of this Court, to be without <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>emedy in the Premiſes, for all which cauſes, the ſaid Complainants prayed the proceſs of this Court againſt the ſaid De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendants, <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, <hi>Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Jernegan</hi> the younger, and <hi>Thomas Neaſt</hi> to anſwer the Premiſes, and to ſhew cauſe why the ſaid Cuſtoms hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore agreed upon, between the ſaid <hi>Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y Jernegan</hi> the elder, and the Tenants of the ſaid Manner of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> and the other before-mentioned Cuſtoms ſhould not ſtand and be retified by the decree of this Court, as by the ſaid Bill of complaints of the ſaid Tenants, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining of Record in this Court appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, unto which Bill the ſaid Defendants made their anſwer in this Court; and firſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder did, in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd by his ſeveral anſwers, in ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance confeſs all the ſaid Cuſtoms alledg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the ſaid complainants Bill, and confeſſed the making of the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denture by himſelf, unto the ſaid Tenants, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd ſaid that he had ſince continued and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>llowed of the ſaid Cuſtoms, and was <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>till ready and willing to approve and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ow thereof, according to the true intent
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:154272:17"/>of the ſaid Indenture of Articles, and confeſſed that he had made a conveyance of the ſaid Mannor of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> uſe of his ſaid Son, the other Defendant, which he ſaid he hoped was not prejudici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al to the ſaid Cuſtoms; and the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, and <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Neaſt</hi> by their ſaid anſwer ſaid, <hi>That during the Minority of any Infant, to whom any Copy-hold Lands of the ſaid Mannor did deſcend upon, by the Death of his Anceſtors, the Lord of the ſaid Manner ought to have the Wardſhip and Cuſtody of the ſaid Lands;</hi> and that he the ſaid <hi>Henry Jerne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan</hi> the younger, by vertue thereof ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Right to the Cuſtomary Lands of the ſaid <hi>William Barns,</hi> did grant the ſame Lands unto the other Defendant <hi>Thomas Neaſt,</hi> and the ſaid Defendants <hi>Henry Jornegan</hi> the younger, and <hi>Thomas Neaſt</hi> did by their ſaid anſwers traverſe and deny the reſidue of the points of the ſaid Bill, and ſo concluded their ſaid an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, as by the ſaid ſeveral anſwers alſo remaining of Record in this Court more fully and at large appeared, whereunto the ſaid Complainants replyed, and the ſaid Parties being at Iſſue, a Commiſſion Iſſued out of this Court for Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:154272:17"/>of Witneſſes on both Parts, which being returned, and according to the ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary rules of this Court, publiſhed a day for hearing of the ſaid cauſe, was by this Court appointed in the laſt <hi>Trini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Term,</hi> as well upon the ſaid Bill exhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bited by the ſaid Mr <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, againſt the ſaid Tenants Defendants, as on the ſaid Bill exhibited by the ſaid Tenants Complainants, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt them the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the younger, and <hi>Thomas Neaſt</hi> Defendants, at which day, being the Eight day of <hi>June</hi> laſt, For as much as upon the entring into the hearing of the matter that day, in the preſence of the Councel, learned on both Parts, for the touching the Cuſtoms of the ſaid Mannor, this Court thought it fit, for avoiding further Controverſie and Suits, that ſome indifferent Perſons might, upon conſideration had of all the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mr <hi>Jernegan,</hi> and the Copies of the Tenants, mediate an end between the Parties, ſo as the ſaid Mr <hi>Jernegan,</hi> Lord of the ſaid Mannor, might have that which apper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained unto him in reaſonable proportion, and that he might uſe his Tenants lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vingly
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:154272:18"/>and kindly, upon their ſubmiſſive carriage towards him, whereunto the Council on both Parts aſſented; it wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> therefore then amongſt other things, or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered that the matter ſhould be refered to Mr <hi>Thorsby</hi> one of the Maſters of this Court, and Mr. <hi>Bridgman,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventre</hi> being of Council with the Parties to the end that they three upon the ſight of all the Court Rolls of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, and all the ancient Copies of the ſaid Tenant, which were all to be brought before them upon the Oathes of the Parties, and alſo upon fight of de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſitions of Witneſſes taken in this cauſe, the depoſition of ſuch Witneſſes as were Tenants only excepted, of whoſe Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony the Court gave no allowance, might treat, mediate, and ſet down ſome good end between the Parties if they could, if not, that then they ſhould cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie this Court the difference between them, whereupon ſuch further order ſhould be taken in the cauſe, as ſhould be meet, according to which order the ſaid Mr <hi>Thorſby,</hi> Mr <hi>Bridgman</hi> and Mr <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventre</hi> made their Certificate to this Court, in manner and form following, that is to ſay, <hi>The Twenty ſeventh day of
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:154272:18"/>November, One Thouſand Six Hundred and Thirteen; between</hi> Henry Jernegan <hi>the younger <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Complainant, and the Cuſtomary Tenants of the Mannor of</hi> Paynſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wicke <hi>in the County of</hi> Glouceſter <hi>Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants; and between the ſaid Tenants Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plainants, and the aforeſaid</hi> Henry Jernegan <hi>Defendant, by warrant of an Order of the Eight of</hi> June <hi>laſt: We have conſidered of the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mannor brought before <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>s by the ſaid</hi> Jernegan, <hi>and the Copies brought before <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>s by the ſaid Tenants, and alſo of the depoſitions of Witneſſes taken in this cauſe; and we have alſo adviſedly peru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed the Indenture made by</hi> Henry Jernegan <hi>the elder <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Father of the Plaintiff, and finding the ſame in divers Articles, rather by the unskilful Penning thereof, then for any matter of ſubſtance to vary, both from the Rolls and Witneſſes, we have thought good to explain the ſame in ſuch ſort as followeth.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Firſt,</hi> Whereas it is contained in the Sixth Article of the ſaid Indenture, that every Surrender made into the hands of the Reeve or his Deputy, ought to be preſented at the next Court, or elſe the ſame to be void, we find that ſuch Sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>render may be preſented at or before the
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:154272:19"/>next general Court of the ſaid Mannor, commonly called the Law-day, and hold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en within the Month after either of the Feaſts of <hi>Eaſter</hi> or St <hi>Michael</hi> the arch-Angel, and upon every ſuch Surrender made, the Lord is to have his Heriot, if the Tenement be heriotable, of ſuch Cattle or Goods as the Tenant had at the time of the ſaid Surrender ſo made to the Reeve or his Deputy, or at any time after.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas,</hi> it is contained in the One and Twentieth Article of the ſame Indenture, that after the Death of every Tenant, dying ſeized of any Lands or Tenement within the ſaid Mannor, Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation ſhall be made at the next Court, and at two other next Courts, and if none come to challenge the ſame Lands, then the ſame Lands ſhall eſcheat to the Lord.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And</hi> in the Seven and Twentieth Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticle of the ſame Indenture it is contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that the Tenants for Waſte done, ſhall be pained at two Courts, and at a third Court upon pain of fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>feiture; we are of opinion, upon view of the ſaid Rolls and depoſitions, that the Courts mentioned in the ſaid two laſt mentioned
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:154272:19" rendition="simple:additions"/>Articles, are to be taken for the two general Courts uſually holden within the ſaid Mannor, within one Month af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Feaſt of <hi>Eaſter,</hi> and St <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch-Angel, commonly called <hi>Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>days,</hi> and that no Tenant of the ſaid Mannor, ſhall incur any prejudice or da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage by reaſon of the not doing of any thing contained in the ſaid Articles, or either of them, ſo as the ſame be done at ſuch general Court or Courts as is afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; and whereas the ſaid Seven and Twentieth Article concerning Waſte, by the words thereof doth ſeem to extend only to the letting down of Houſes, we are of opinion that the ſame was meant and intended to extend to all Waſtes and decayes in Houſes, and this we conceive was the true meaning of the Parties, how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever the ſaid Indenture be ſomewhat imperfectly penned.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas</hi> in the Eleventh Article of the ſame Indenture it is declared, that after the Death of a Woman holding by her free Bench the Tenement or Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments wherein her tenure ſhall come to the next Heir, on her part of the Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band of the ſame Woman, and for lack of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>uch Heir to the next Kinſman of the
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:154272:20"/>ſaid Husband; we do find that the Cuſtom of the Mannor is and ſo wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> meant to have been declared by the ſaid Article, that after the Death of ſuch a Woman, ſuch Tenements ſhall diſiend to the Heirs of the ſame Husband accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the courſe of the common Law, and not otherwiſe.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And</hi> whereas by the Thirteenth Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticle of the ſame Indenture it is declared, that all Tenants by their Cuſtom, may fell Woods, Timber or Trees upon their Tenement; we do not find it warranted by any Rolls or other proof, that any Tenant holding by free Bench or other wayes for Life, may fell any Woods, Timber or Trees, except for their neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary Boots, to be ſpent and imployed upon the ſaid Tenements, and therefore we hold it meet, that the ſaid Article as to ſo much thereof, as concerneth the felling any Wood, Timber, or Trees, to be explained not to extend but only to ſuch Tenants as have Eſtates of Inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And</hi> where in the ſame Thirteenth Article of the Indenture it is declared, that every Cuſtomary Tenant may be<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and Let his Lands without Licence; we find the ſame
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:154272:20"/>Cuſtom warranted by ſundry proofs; howbeit we find it proved, that ſuch Leaſe is to hold no longer then to the Feaſt of St <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch-Angel, next after the Death of him or her that made it, and in cauſe of Death to be deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined at <hi>Michaelmas</hi> after ſuch Death, or by Surrender, or Forfeiture of the Eſtate, in the mean time for what term of Years ſoever the ſaid Leaſe be made, and ſo much we hold meet to be added, in the explaina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid Article.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And</hi> where by the Twentieth Article of the ſame Indenture it is declared, how and in what ſort the Daughters of any Cuſtomary Tenant of the ſaid Mannor, ought to divide the Inheritance of their Anceſtors; we hold it meet to be added by way of explaination of the ſaid Article, that in caſe any one or more of the ſaid Daughters of ſuch Copy-holders, happen to dye either in the life time or after the death of ſuch Copy-holder, that the Heir or Heirs of her or them ſo dying, ought to have the like benefit in every reſpect, for and touching any thing contained in the ſaid Article, as the Party or Parties dying ſhould or ought to have had if he or they had happened to live.</p>
            <pb n="36" facs="tcp:154272:21"/>
            <p>
               <hi>And</hi> concerning the Fourteenth and Five and Twentieth Article of the ſaid Indenture, we do not find the ſame war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranted by any proofs, nor do hold them fit to be coutinued, but are of opinion that the ſame ſhall be henceforth utterly diſallowed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>But</hi> concerning the rates of Fines, both upon Death and Surrender, being the matter chiefly controverted between the ſaid Lord and Tenants; we find pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved both by depoſition of Witneſſes, and by ſundry Copies and Rolls of the times of <hi>King Edward</hi> the Sixth, <hi>Queen Mary</hi> and <hi>Queen Elizabeth,</hi> and ſome of antienter times, that the Tenants upon Surrenders uſed to pay four Years Rent for their Fines, and upon decent one Years Rent for their Fines; and in this we find a very conſtant courſe with little or no variance for Threeſcore Years now paſt or more, until by the ſaid Indenture the Fines upon Surrenders were raiſed from four unto ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Years Rent, at which rate they have continued ever ſince the making of the ſaid Indenture, and therefore we are of opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on that it is very meet, that the Fines of the Tenants of the ſaid Mannor, ſhall be continued and payed in certainty, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:154272:21"/>to the ſaid Indenture, and that no fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther queſtion be hereafter moved by the Lords of the ſaid Mannor, that are or ſhall be concerning the ſaid point of incer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainty of Fine; after conſideration had of all which things we found ſome diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culty how to compoſe the ſaid cauſe, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs we could ſettle ſome other Queſtions not mentioned in the ſaid Indenture, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the ſaid Lord and Tenants, and therefore by aſſent and with the good liking of all the ſaid Parties, we took conſideration thereof alſo, and to that purpoſe, whereas ſome queſtion hath been between the ſaid Lord and Tenants, for that the Lord claimed to have the ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip of the ſaid Tenants Heirs being within Age, to his own uſe, for as much as it appeared to us, that upon that point there hath been a Tryal by verdict at the common Law, which paſt againſt the Lord, we hold it meet that the Lord for the time being, be henceforth for ever excluded, to have any further benefit or power, by colour or pretence of ſuch ward, but only the committing of ſuch Heir to ſome of his near Kindred, by the advice of the Homage, for which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitment the Lord for the time being ſhall
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:154272:22"/>have for a Fine three Years Rent and no more, ſaving one Years Rent more which the Lord is alſo to have in every ſuch cauſe, in reſpect of the diſſent to the Heir, and if any Lands ſhall afterwards defend to ſuch Heir during his non age, then the Lord ſhall have the like Fine and Fines in every reſpect, according to the Rent of the Land ſo newly deſcended, as he had or ſhall have upon the firſt commitment. And whereas there are within the ſaid Mannor, ſundry Lands called by the name of the <hi>Demeaſue, Lands,</hi> which we find hath been time out of mind accuſtomed to paſs by Copy, and nevertheleſs becauſe they are called <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meaſues,</hi> the Lord hath of late made queſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on whether they are grantable by Copy or not, a thing in our opinions of ſmall weight, to ſhake the validity of a thing ſo long continued. And there alſo within the ſaid Mannor, certain Lands called <hi>Chantry-Lands,</hi> which being but of ſmall quantity, and lying intermixed amongſt the Copy-holds of the ſaid Mannor, have of long time been granted by Copy of Court Roll. And there is alſo a certain Ground called <hi>Wickerige-hill,</hi> which the Lord Pretendeth hath been parcels of the Waſte of the ſaid Mannor, but we find that
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:154272:22"/>by long continued uſage, the Tenants have enjoyed ſeveral parcels thereof, as part of their Tenements which they hold by Copy; we are of opinion that it is meet, that the ſame <hi>Demeaſue-Lands</hi> and <hi>Chantry-Lands,</hi> ſhall be accounted and enjoyed as Copy-hold, by the reſpective owners thereof: And that the ſaid par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cel of <hi>Wickerige-hill,</hi> ſhall be for ever here after likewiſe enjoyed by the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Owners and Poſſeſſors thereof, in like ſort as now it is, without further claim, let or interuption of the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan,</hi> or of any other that ſhall be Lord of the ſaid Mannor, ſaving that the Lord may put in his Cattel there as a Commoner at all times, when the ſame Ground ſhall lie fallen, or otherwiſe open to the Waſte next adjoyning thereunto. And whereas their is another queſtion be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the ſaid Lord and Tenants, touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Fines to be payed to the Lord upon any exchange of any Land, to be made amongſt the Tenants; we find that the ſaid Tenants have uſed to make ſuch exchanges, paying for every Acre to the Lord of the ſaid Mannor for his Fine, the ſum of four Pence, which rate we <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>old meet ſhould be ratified, allowed, and
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:154272:23"/>confirmed for ever: Theſe things be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſo digeſted, we moved the Tenants that they would be content to raiſe among them, ſome reaſonable ſum of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, to be beſtowed on their Land-Lord, for his favour and good will, which they very dutifully, and lovingly yielded unto, and upon our motion did agree, to pay unto him, the ſum of One Thouſand Four Hundred and Fifty Pound; that is to ſay, Five Hundred and Fifty Pounds, at or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the fifth day of <hi>December</hi> now next coming, Four Hundred and Fifty Pounds upon the fifth day of <hi>December,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our <hi>Lord God,</hi> 1614. at the Church Porch of <hi>Paynſwicke,</hi> and Four Hundred and Fifty Pounds reſidue, upon the fifth day of <hi>December,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our <hi>Lord God,</hi> 1615. at the place aforeſaid; which money we have wiſhed, and the ſaid Mr <hi>Je<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>negan</hi> hath under taken ſhall be beſtowed in ſuch ſort, that the benefit thereof may redown not only to himſelf, but unto his Wife, who hath a Joynture in the ſaid Mannor, and to his Son and Heir <hi>John Jernegan,</hi> in whom we find the Inheritance of the ſaid Mannor expectant upon his Fathers Death, is by good conveyance ſettled;
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:154272:23"/>and the ſaid Tenants have likwiſe aſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, that whereas by the ſaid Indenture it is declared, that they ought to have the Herbage and Panage of the common Woods, common Hills, and Waſtes of the ſaid Mannor; and it ſtandeth proved by Witneſſes, that they ever enjoyed the ſame, and the Lord hath been wholly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded thereof: The Lord of the ſaid Mannor for the time being, may for the better breeding and increaſe of Wood, incloſe one full third part of all the Woods, and Wood grounds of the ſaid Mannor, which do now lie open and in common, ſaving the Waſte ground cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, <hi>Sponbed-hill</hi> alias <hi>Kimsbury-hill,</hi> whereof he may alſo incloſe Five and Twenty Acres, in ſuch places and man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, as the ſame parts ſo to be incloſed, have been lately ſet out by the Lord and Tenants; and that the ſaid Lord may keep the ſame parts ſo incloſed, from time to time according to the Statutes in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half; and alſo that the Lord of the ſaid Mannor for the time being, ſhall have common with the ſaid Tenants, in the Waſte and commonable Grounds afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, after the Rate and Proportion of two yard Lands and no more, for the
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:154272:24"/>Land the ſaid Lord <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ow hath, and for ſuch Lands as the Lord of the ſaid Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor ſhall hereafter happen to have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon, after ſuch Rate and Proportion, as the Tenants of the ſaid Mannor have o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhall have, wherewith the ſaid Mr <hi>Jerne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan</hi> is well contented; in <hi>Reſpect</hi> of all which we hold it meet, if it ſhall ſo ſeem meet to this honorable Court, that the ſaid Indenture with ſuch explanations, alterati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and additions as are before ſet down, with other the premiſes by us before thought meet to be done and performed, ſhould be ratified by the decree, &amp; authority of this honorable Court, againſt the ſaid <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder, and <hi>Henry Jer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>negan</hi> the younger, and <hi>Elinor</hi> his Wife, and <hi>John Jernegan</hi> his Son and Heir, ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parent, their and every of their Heirs and Aſſigns, and againſt all and every Perſon and Perſons, having or lawfully claiming, or that ſhall hereafter have or lawfully claim, from, by or under them, or any of them, the rather for that the ſaid Mr <hi>Jer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>negan</hi> the elder, at the time of the mak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſaid Indenture, was owner of the Inheritance of the ſaid Mannor; and for that we conceive, the ſaid Tenants have given for bying their Peace, a very
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:154272:24"/>ample and liberal ſatisfaction to their Landlord, not inferior in our opinions, to the true worth of any benefit they ſhall, or may receive by this Order; and to the end the ſaid Mr <hi>Jernegan</hi> may be ſecured of the Money, agreed to be payed unto him, and an even courſe may be held, for the ſatisfying all charges ſuſtained in this buſineſs, we have cauſed the ſaid Tenants among themſelves, to make a Taxation, what every of them is to pay, as well to ſatisfie the ſaid Money payable to Mr <hi>Jer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>negan,</hi> as all charges incident to this buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, which Taxation is ſet down in a <hi>Schedule,</hi> to theſe preſents annexed; and we hold it meet, if any the Perſons there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by taxed, ſhall make default of payment of any the Sums by them payable, the Lands and Tenements of him that ſhall make ſuch default, may by order of this Court be Sequeſtred, into the hands of any meet Perſons, to be nominated by the ſaid Mr <hi>Jernegan,</hi> as well for contributi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to be made to ſuch of the Tenants, as have already given ſecurity for the ſaid payment, and undergone the charges of this buſineſs, as for the ſatisfation of the ſaid Mr <hi>Jernegan</hi> for the reſidue, with da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages for the forbearance thereof, after
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:154272:25"/>the rate of fifteen in the Hundred; and all the charges in the procuring, or exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuting the ſaid ſequeſtration; which <hi>Sche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dule</hi> annexed unto the ſaid Certificate, fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loweth in manner and form following, that is to ſay, <hi>A Schedule</hi> containing the Names of the Copy-holders of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor of <hi>Paynſwicke</hi> in the County of <hi>Glou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſter,</hi> and what Sums every of them is to pay for their ſeveral Tenements, and at what days, according to the report of <hi>Henry Thorsby</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> one of the Maſters of the high Court of <hi>Chancery, John Bridgman</hi> and <hi>Thomas Coventry</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> made in the ſaid Court of <hi>Chancery,</hi> the ſeven and Twentieth day of <hi>November, Anno Regni Regis Jacobi <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ndecimo.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="part">
               <p>SUms to be payed the fifth of <hi>December</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred and thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen, <hi>John Biſhopp,</hi> eleven Pound three Shillings four Pence, <hi>Richard Knowles,</hi> five Pound, <hi>John Tickle</hi> eight Pound five Shillings, <hi>John King</hi> eight Pound, <hi>Thomas Caſtle</hi> twelve Pound eight Shillings ſix Pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ce, <hi>Elizabeth King</hi> five Pound five Shillings, <hi>Robert King</hi> four Pounds, <hi>John
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:154272:25" rendition="simple:additions"/>Poole</hi> eleven Pounds ten Pence, <hi>Thomas Gardiner</hi> ſenior, <hi>Thomas Gardiner</hi> junior, thirteen Pound, <hi>John Gyde</hi> ſeven Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>John Winchcome</hi> five Pounds fourteen Shillings, <hi>William Twening</hi> ſeven Pounds ſixteen Shillings, <hi>Anthony Gardi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner</hi> five Pounds, <hi>John Mower</hi> fourteen Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>John Gardiner</hi> of <hi>Haſcome,</hi> five Pounds, <hi>John Tunly</hi> five Pounds, <hi>Thomas Wine</hi> eight Pounds, <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zabeth Hawkins</hi> five Pounds, <hi>John Beard</hi> four Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>Thomas Vaughan</hi> three Pounds nineteen Shillings ſix Pence, <hi>William Widdow</hi> one Pound twelve Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Thomas Short</hi> two Pounds two Shillings, <hi>John Ruſſel</hi> three Pounds five Shillings, <hi>Robert Harris</hi> one Pound ſix Shillings, <hi>William King</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>John Hunt</hi> four Shillings ſix Pence, <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Bangerfeild</hi> three Shillings, <hi>John Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> Docter of Law, one Pound ten Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Thomas Hilman</hi> four Pounds two Shillings, <hi>Thomas Pitt</hi> ſeven Pounds, <hi>Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Mayo</hi> five Pounds, <hi>Richard Gardiner</hi> nine <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſix Pence, <hi>Thomas Weſt</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>Peter Bird</hi> three Pound five Shillings, <hi>Thomas Andrews</hi> ſixteen Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Thomas Flamberd</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Alice Syford</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Humphery Whiteaker</hi>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:154272:26" rendition="simple:additions"/>eight Shillings, <hi>Adam <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ingell</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Henry Lord</hi> eleven Shillings, <hi>William Myll</hi> two Pounds, <hi>Walter Coocke</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>William Harding</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Francis Harding</hi> eleven Shillings, <hi>William Heath</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Harding Widdow</hi> nine Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Jone Pilſon</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Thomas Coles</hi> one Shilling, <hi>Patrick Tickle</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>William Twening</hi> three Pounds, <hi>John Clarke</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>William Hawkins</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Thomas Motly</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Little</hi> ſix Shillings <hi>Thomas Jenkins</hi> two Pounds five Shillings, <hi>John Fream</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>William Rice</hi> eleven Shillings, <hi>Robert Clutterbuck</hi> one Pound ſeven Shilling, <hi>John Holder</hi> four Pounds ſix Shillings ſix Pence, <hi>Gyles Wheler</hi> three Pounds ſix Shilling eight Pence, <hi>Gyles Arther</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Gybbens</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Reylocke Widdow</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Edward Gardner</hi> one Pound, <hi>Michael Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Stama<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e</hi> eight Shils. <hi>Thomas Williams</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>William Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſilton</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>Cooke Widdow, James Cooke</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>John Cooke</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Eliener Warren</hi> three Shillings ſix Pence, <hi>Elizabeth Cooper</hi> eighteen Shillings, <hi>George Sturmy</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Corbet</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Henry Ridler</hi> ſixteen Shillings, <hi>William Wren</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Ann Jackes</hi> ſix
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:154272:26" rendition="simple:additions"/>Shillings, <hi>Julian J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ces</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Eli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor Jaques</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Thomas <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> ten Shillings, <hi>William Hewling</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>John Streate</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Toby Myll</hi> four Shillings four Pence, <hi>Richard Pitt</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Gardiner</hi> two Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>John Badger</hi> two Pounds, <hi>Ann Whitehorn</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Adams</hi> and <hi>William Linnet</hi> two pounds, <hi>Edmond Gynner</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Richard Banc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knot</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>Samuel Davis</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Nicholas Aſhman</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>William Maſon</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Robert Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> one Pound nine Shillings, <hi>Richard King</hi> ſix Pounds two Shillings eight Pence, <hi>Thomas Kyne</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>James Myll</hi> ſixteen Shillings, <hi>Richard Sellors</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>William Niblet</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Ann Cooper</hi> one Pound eleven Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Thomas Creeſe</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Richard Smyth</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Hayes</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>Amie Hoocke</hi> and <hi>Thomas Knowles</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Robert Long</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Thomas Gybbins</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Court Hooper</hi> one Pound eight Shillings ſix Pence, <hi>William Loe</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Joan Wren</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>Margaret King</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>John Twening</hi> ten Pounds, <hi>John Twening</hi> of <hi>Wergine,</hi> three
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:154272:27"/>puonds ſixteen Shiiling, <hi>Henry Aldredg</hi> Fifty Shillings, <hi>William Blyſs</hi> five pounds ten Shillings, <hi>William Barns</hi> ten Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>William Clyſſold</hi> ten Pounds, <hi>Widdow Clyſſo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d</hi> ten Pounds, <hi>Thomas Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret</hi> five Pounds, <hi>Thomas Blyſe</hi> five Pounds, <hi>Thomas Loveday</hi> ſix Pounds nine Shillings, <hi>Edmond Flecher</hi> twenty nine Pounds ſix Shillings eight Pence, <hi>John Mayo</hi> ſixteen Pounds, <hi>John Jordane</hi> ſeventeen Pounds, <hi>Widdow Ockey</hi> three Pounds ſixteen Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Richard Flecher</hi> four Shillings, <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Flecher</hi> four Shillings, <hi>John Brown</hi> eleven Pounds, <hi>Richard Gardiner</hi> and his <hi>Wife,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Merret</hi> ſix Pounds, <hi>John Loveday</hi> two Pounds fifteen Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>Edward Hitchins</hi> twelve Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>Thomas Tayler</hi> eleven Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>John Gardiner</hi> three Pounds ſix Shillings, <hi>George Phelps</hi> five Pounds, <hi>Ann Blyſs, Viz.</hi> eight Pounds five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>John Phillipts</hi> five Pound five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>John Weſt</hi> five, <hi>Corbers viz.</hi> four Shillings, <hi>John Daber</hi> four Shilling, <hi>Chriſtopher Freame</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Robert Eſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ington</hi> four Shillings, <hi>William Povie</hi> four Shillings four Pence. <hi>Thomas Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> four Shillings four Pen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e, <hi>John Wats</hi> one Shilling, <hi>Thomas Cliffold</hi> one Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling,
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:154272:27"/>
                  <hi>Richard W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ob</hi> one Shilling, <hi>Henry Flecher</hi> one Shilling, <hi>Gyles <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ardner</hi> one Shilling, <hi>John Baugh</hi> twelve Pounds, <hi>John Watkins</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>x Pounds, <hi>Thomas Byſhopp</hi> ten Pounds, <hi>Richard Gardner</hi> and <hi>William Mayle</hi> twenty ſeven Pounds thirteen Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings; <hi>Thomas Hurrupp</hi> thirteen Pounds eleven Shillings, <hi>William Osborne</hi> ninteen Pounds thirteen Shillings four Pence, <hi>Wal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Tocknel</hi> three Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Wilſhe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e</hi> fifty Shillings, <hi>Richard Gard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner</hi> ſeven Pounds five Shillings, <hi>William Bennet</hi> five Pounds, <hi>John Gyde</hi> junior thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Shillings two Pence, <hi>William Mayle</hi> one Pound fifteen Shillings, <hi>John Tomes</hi> one Pound ſeven Shillings, <hi>Elenor Pyper</hi> two Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>William Tom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kins</hi> one Pound five Shillings, <hi>William Andrews</hi> one Pound five Shillings, <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Coocke</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>Thomas Knowles</hi> twelve Shillings, <hi>William Wat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kins</hi> eighteen Shillings, <hi>Hawkins</hi> vid. ſix Shillings, <hi>Michael Harding</hi> ſix Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>John Myll</hi> three Shillings, <hi>Rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ard Myll</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Sharp</hi> vid. ſix Shillings, <hi>Arther Hillman</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Je<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ffery Ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>field</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>William T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ckell</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Henry Wheler</hi> one Pound ſeventeen Shillings ſix Pence,
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:154272:28"/>
                  <hi>William Mayo</hi> eight Shi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ings four pence <hi>John Osborn</hi> one Pound one Shilling, <hi>John Walkby</hi> ten Shillings, <hi>Steven Coock</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Webb</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>William Shewell</hi> ſixteen Shillings, <hi>Rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ard Deane</hi> three Pounds eleven Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings ſix Pence, <hi>John Osborn</hi> four Pounds, <hi>Richard Coocke</hi> five Pounds four Shillings two pence, <hi>Robert Coocke</hi> two <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ounds ſixteen Shillings, <hi>John Weſt</hi> ſeven Pounds, <hi>Robert Weſt</hi> eight Pounds nine Shillings, <hi>Walter Humphreys</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>John Gly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford</hi> ſix Shillings, <hi>Henry Clement</hi> two Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>James Collins</hi> two Shillings, <hi>Thomas Whiting</hi> three Pounds fifteen Shillings, <hi>John Shott</hi> two Pounds ten Shillings, <hi>John Poole</hi> ten Pounds, <hi>John Gardener</hi> two Pounds ten Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, <hi>William Loveday</hi> nine Pound fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Shillings ſix pence, <hi>John Whiting</hi> four Pounds one Shilling four pence, <hi>Henry Stamage</hi> eight Shillings, <hi>Thomas Green</hi> three Pounds fifteen Shillings, <hi>Thomas Browne</hi> one Shilling, <hi>Ailce Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lins</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>James Collins</hi> twelve Shillings; <hi>Thom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>s Smart</hi> one Shilling.</p>
               <p>In the Decree its ſet down the Tenants are to pay one Thouſand four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred and fifty Pounds, at three pays,
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:154272:28"/>the firſt pay is <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ve hundred and fifty Pounds, which is hear ſet down as in the Decree, the other two pays, which is four hundred and fifty Pounds a peice, the Tenants are taxed two ſeveral times more, and ſet down at large as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to be payed the fifth of <hi>Decem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber,</hi> 1614. and the fifth of <hi>December,</hi> 1615.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="52" facs="tcp:154272:29"/>
               <p>UNto the which <hi>Schedule,</hi> as alſo to the ſaid <hi>Certificate,</hi> the ſaid Mr <hi>Thorsby,</hi> Mr <hi>Bridgman</hi> and Mr <hi>Coventrey,</hi> have ſubſcribed their names, as by the ſaid <hi>Schedule</hi> and <hi>Certificate</hi> remaining of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord with the Regiſter of this Court ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peareth, upon all which proceeding it pleaſed this Court on the nine and Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth day of <hi>November,</hi> to order and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree this Cauſe as followeth; Where<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y an order of the eight of <hi>June</hi> laſt, the matter in queſtion between the ſaid par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, was referred to Mr <hi>Thorſby</hi> one of the Maſters of this Court, and to Mr <hi>Bridgman</hi> and Mr <hi>Coventrey</hi> being of Councel with the parties, to the end that they three upon the ſight of all the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mannor, and all the ancient Copies of the ſaid Tenants, which were all to be brought before them, upon the Oaths of the parties, and alſo upon ſight of the depoſitions of Witneſſes taken in the caſe, the depoſitions of ſuch Witnſſees as are Tenants only excepted, of whoſe Teſtimony the Court giveth no allowance might treat, mediate and ſet
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:154272:29"/>down ſome good e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d between the parties if they could, if not, then to certifie the differences between them, where upon ſuch further order ſhould be taken in the cauſe as ſhould be meet; for as much as this Court was this day informed by Mr <hi>Lawrance Hide,</hi> being of Councel with the ſaid Tenants, that the ſaid Mr <hi>Thorſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by,</hi> and the ſaid Mr <hi>Bridgman</hi> and Mr <hi>Coventrey</hi> have according to the ſaid or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, conſidered of the Court Rolls of the ſaid Mann or brought before them by the ſaid Plaintiff <hi>Jernegan,</hi> and the Copies brought before them by the ſaid Tenants, and of the depoſitions taken in the cauſe; and have alſo adviſedly peru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed the indenture made by <hi>Henry Jernegan</hi> the elder <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Father of the Plaintiff, and have thereupon made a full and abſolute end of the cauſe, and ſet down the ſame very exactly under their hands, and cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified into this Court, which was now ſhewed forth and offered to be read; It is the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>efore this preſent Term of St <hi>Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chael,</hi> that is to ſay on <hi>Monday</hi> the nine and twentieth day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Year of the Reign of our Gracious So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraign Lord <hi>James,</hi> by the Grace of God of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi>
                  <pb n="54" facs="tcp:154272:30"/>King defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That is to ſay of <hi>England, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> the Eleventh, and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the Seven and Fortieth, by the right honorable <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas</hi> Lord <hi>Elleſmert,</hi> Lord Chancellour of <hi>England,</hi> and by the whole Court of Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cery Ordered and Decreed, that the ſaid Certificate, and all the matters therein contained are and be ratified and confirm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Decree and Authority of this Court, and the ſeveral ſums of Money limited and ſet down in the <hi>Schedule,</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in the ſaid Certificate, to be payed by the ſaid Tenants at the days and times expreſſed in the ſaid <hi>Schedule,</hi> and all the reſt of the matter in the ſaid Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate contained, are decreed to be perfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med to all intents and purpoſes, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the tenor and true meaning thereof.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <pb n="55" facs="tcp:154272:30"/>
            <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
               <p>
                  <hi>NOs autem tenorem irrotu lamenti de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creti predict ad requiſitio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes Willi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lmi Osburne et Edmundi Flecher et alio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum Tenentium Manerij predicti duximus Exem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plifican per preſentes in cujus rei Teſtimonium has litteras noſtras fieri fecimus Patentes teſte me ipſo apud Weſtmin. primo die Februarij Anno Regni noſtri Angliae, Franciae, et Hiberniae duo decimo eScocia qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dragiſſimo Octavo.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ur per nos,</hi>
                     <list>
                        <item>M. Carew</item>
                        <item>J. Hone.</item>
                     </list> 
                     <hi>Cleric.</hi>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
               <p>VVEe therefore the tenor of the Inrollment of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree afore ſaid; at the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt of the ſaid <hi>William Oſborn,</hi> and <hi>Edmond Flech<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er,</hi> and other the Tenant<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> of the Mannor aforeſaid, have cauſed to be exem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plified by theſe Preſents, in Witneſs of which we have cauſed theſe our Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, to be made Pattents witneſs our ſelves at <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter,</hi> the firſt day of <hi>February,</hi> in the year of our Raign of <hi>England, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> the Twelth, and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the eight and Fortieth.</p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Examined by We,
<list>
                        <item>
                           <hi>Mathew Care<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </hi> and</item>
                        <item>
                           <hi>John Hone.</hi>
                        </item>
                     </list> 
                     <hi>Clerks.</hi>
                  </signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
            <trailer>FIN</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:31"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:31"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:32"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:32"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:33"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:33"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:34"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:34"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:35"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154272:35" rendition="simple:additions"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
